《小鬼当家 真爱宝藏》
看房开放日 待售 加文·华盛顿
看房开放日 待售
我们的厨房连着那边的一个小餐厅
And our kitchen connects to a little dining room right over there.
您说过您想要开放式的厨房
Now you mentioned you wanted an open concept.
太好了 我超喜欢开放式设计 是啊
Cool，I am obsessed with open concept。Yes.
我最爱的就是开放式设计
Open is my favorite concept.
这两位是房主 帕姆和杰夫·麦肯齐
Well，here they are，Pam and Jeff McKenzie，the owners.
我刚刚跟布莱克金夫妇说 他们也许可以
I was just telling the Breckins that they could probably knock down
打掉一些墙 打造一个开阔宽敞的空间
some of these walls and make it one，big，open space.
千万别生气噢 是啊
Not mad at that。Yes.
那你们得当心了
Well，you just wanna be careful，
因为如果你们打的是承重墙
'cause if those are loadbaring walls and you knock one down，
整栋房子会坍塌的
the whole place could collapse.
真的吗 好郁闷
Mmm。Bummer。Really？
这又不是积木叠的房子 杰夫
Um，it's not a Jenga tower，Jeff.
这不是积木叠的房子 杰夫
It's not a Jenga tower，Jeff.
帕姆是温内特卡小学的老师
And Pam is a teacher at Winnetka Elementary.
对吗 好的 附近的学校都超级棒
Am I right？Yes。The schools here are amazing.
对吗 杰夫
Correct，Jeff？
对 有好几所是州里的一流学校 它们真的棒棒的
Um，yeah。Some of the best in the state。They are totally lit.
沃 哦
Aw。Oh.
它们配了新的金属探测器以后就更棒了
Especially since they put in new metal detectors.
好吧 杰夫 你胡说什么
Oh。Okay。Jeff。What are you doing？
杰夫 你可以去给大家拿瓶装水吗
Uh，Jeff，uh，could you go get some more bottled water to everyone.
可以
Yep.
你可以去多拿点瓶装水吗
Can you get some more bottled water？
那个 好的
Ooh。Mmhmm。Yep.
他就是那样
Jeff.
妈妈 我真的要尿尿 你怎么又要尿尿了
Mum，I really have to pee。I cannot believe you need to go again.
我说了让你用咖啡馆的洗手间
I told you to use the restroom in the coffee shop.
斯图叔叔用过的厕所我可不敢上
After Uncle Stu had been in there？Really？
你看到他在午餐时吃了多少芥末蘸蛋吗
Did you see how many deviled eggs he had for lunch？
天啊
Oh，goodness。Um.
那你只能等我们到家再说了
You'll just have to wait till we get home.
你确定吗 你想想
You sure about that？Do the maths.
一个十岁小孩的小膀胱 装着六杯汽水可撑不了那么久
Six soda refills into one，tiny，tenyearold's bladder does not go.
我
I'm
看房开放日 加文·华盛顿
好 我有办法了 什么办法
Okay。I've got an idea。What？
你得配合妈妈演戏
You're gonna have to pretend with Mummy.
我们假装我们要买房
We're gonna have to pretend we're going to buy a house.
橘子 汽水 我可以喝一罐吗
Ooh！Can I get one of those？
这得问你的爸爸妈妈
Uh，that might be a question for your parents，
因为它们的含糖量很高
just 'cause there's a lot of sugar in them，so…
好吧
Oh。Fine.
哇 你好高啊 你差不多和弗兰肯斯坦一样高了
Wow，you're so tall。You almost look like Frankenstein.
你想说的是弗兰肯斯坦造的怪物吧 科普一下 弗兰肯斯坦是那个博士
Oh，you mean Frankenstein's monster。Frankenstein is the doctor，FYI.
这些娃娃还真“酷”啊
Uh。Cool dolls.
这不是我的娃娃 是我妈妈的
Well，they're not mine。Um。They belonged to my mother.
你说是就是了
Sure they did.
这个娃娃是怎么回事
Oh！What's wrong with this one？
我不知道
Yeah，I don't know.
但它们很易碎 我们就放着别动吧
But they're very delicate，so why don't we just leave them right there.
有个小公举不想让别人玩他的洋娃娃呢
Oh。Little boy doesn't wanna share his dolly？
你说什么
Excuse me？
我懂了 你是那种人
Ah，I get it。You're one of those guys.
什么意思 我不知道啊 要不然你告诉我？
What do you mean？I don't know。You tell me.
你在这里啊 嗨 妈妈
There you are。Oh！Hi，Mom.
你觉得他像不像弗兰肯斯坦
Doesn't he look like Frankenstein to you？
麦克斯 别胡说 非常抱歉
IMax。I am so sorry.
他不像弗兰肯斯坦 他像弗兰肯斯坦造的怪物
No，he doesn't look like Frankenstein。He looks like Frankenstein's monster.
很抱歉 他刚刚是不是一直在打扰你
I'm sorry。Has he been bothering you？
没有 他很讨人喜欢
No。He's a delight.
他有时候确实很可爱
Aw，well，he has his moments.
这是施耐德人仔吗
Ooh！Is that a Schneider Kinder？
我在《藏宝箱》里看过 就是那个古董节目 我超爱看那个节目
I saw these on Treasure Trunk，that antiques show。I love that show.
有个老太太在一个车库旧货售卖会上 花十美元买了这样的娃娃
There was this elderly lady who'd bought one at a garage sale for about $10.
后来那个娃娃竟然卖了五千美元
And then it ended up going for about $5，000.
哇 一个丑丑的小瓷娃娃竟然值五千美元
Wow，5，000 bucks for an ugly，little porcelain kid.
我卖亲生的娃娃都赚不到一半的钱呢
I didn't get half that for selling my real kids.
是吗
Yeah？
我们得回去了 “好耶”
I think we should go home。Oh，yay.
回家跟九个堂兄弟姐妹抢一个厕所 我好“迫不及待”啊
I can't wait to go home and share one toilet with nine bloomin' cousins.
麦克斯韦·约翰·默瑟 你今天怎么回事
Maxwell Johan Mercer。What is with you today，hmm？
卡罗尔·埃伦·默瑟 你猜猜
Carol Ellen Mercer，take a guess？
你顶嘴是吧 这次我们去东京过圣诞节不带你了
You know what？How's about we just spend Christmas in Tokyo without you？
太好了 让奶奶陪你过节吧
Great idea。I'll leave Grammy with you.
太好了 有奶奶陪
Oh，yes，Grammy。Then you'll have to go to bed
然后你每天晚上都得六点钟就上床睡觉
at 6：00 p.m。every evening and help her with her bath.
还得照顾她洗澡
这么好啊 请问我该去哪里登记报名呢
Oh，that sounds great。Where do I sign up？
回家的路上别想吃麦当劳了
No McDonald's for you on the way home.
什么 妈妈 你不能答应了让孩子吃麦当劳又食言
What？Mum。You can't promise a kid McDonald's and not deliver。Ooh.
真遗憾啊
What a McShame.
太好喝了
Ooh。That's good.
宝贝 回家 上车 我们走
Darling，home。Car。Now。Come on.
对不起 我刚才冲你发脾气了 但我就是搞不懂
I'm sorry I lashed out at you，but I just don't see why
为什么要让每个愚蠢的亲戚都住我们家
we have to share our house with every stupid relative we have.
这可是圣诞节啊
I mean，it's Christmas.
你说到点子上了 圣诞节就是要跟家人一起庆祝
Exactly，and Christmas is all about spending time with family.
就算他们的所作所为 让你焦虑 气愤和发狂也得一起庆祝
Even if everything they do makes you anxious or furious and insane.
因为那是圣诞节的意义所在
Because that is the meaning of Christmas.
好了 麦肯齐先生和夫人 我们已经抛出了鱼饵
All right，McKenzies。We have chummed the.
现在已经有几条大鱼在咬鱼饵了
Chummed the waters。And I think we've gotten a couple of nibbles.
我知道你们想尽快把房子卖出去
Now I know you guys wanna sell as soon as possible，
但我觉得在圣诞季结束之前
but I don't think we're gonna get any major bites
大鱼是不会上钩的
until after the holiday season.
不会吧
I don't know.
杰夫看到有个家伙仔细看了我的内衣抽屉 他看起来很感兴趣呀 不是吗
The guy Jeff saw looking through my underwear drawer seemed interested，no？
是啊 不过他不是对买房感兴趣 不过别担心
Yes，but I don't think in buying the house。But don't worry.
布莱克金夫妇正围着鱼饵转呢 我会重点关注他们的
The Breckins are circling the boat，so I'll stay on top of them.
孩子们回来了
The kids are home.
我们知道怎么⋯ 怎么了
What's happening？
为什么要怕孩子们
Why are we scared of the kids？
我们没跟他们说要卖房
We haven't told them we're selling the house.
嘿
Hey！
嗨
Oh，hi.
孩子们 我以为你们看完电影后会给我们打电话
Hi，guys。I thought you were gonna call after the movie was over.
我们是坐网约车回来的
Oh，no，we just took an Uber.
你还好吗
You good？Oh，yeah.
好啊 我只是在想事情
Yeah，I'm doing some thinking，you know？
这真是个适合思考的好地方
This is a very good spot for thinking.
嗯 嗯
Mmhmm。Mmhmm.
我喜欢这个空间
I love this space。Oh.
你是谁
Who are you？
我是 这是加文 他是
I'm，uh This is Gavin。And he is，um
我是你的私人教练
Your personal trainer。ThatYes.
没错 我要好好训一训 你们肌肉松弛的爸爸
I'm gonna be training your flabby dad。Hmm？
那气球是怎么回事
Balloons？
这些气球是为了庆祝你迈出了第一步
These are a gesture to say congratulations for taking your first step.
恭喜啦 老兄 你确实得好好锻炼了
Congratulations，man。You got to take care of yourself.
我们要跟肥肚腩说拜拜了 对吗
We're gonna get rid of that jelly belly，Dad。Am I right？
跟肥肚腩说拜拜
Get rid of the jelly belly.
还要让他的扁平臀练出肌肉来
We're gonna put some muscle on that flat，pancake butt.
拜托了 加文
Thank you，Gavin。Yeah.
好的 那我就先走了 改天再见
I'm just gonna take off real quick，and I'm gonna see y'all later.
我已经等不及看你练出翘臀了
And I'm looking forward to that butt.
麦卡利斯特 家居安保
我可以玩一下吗 我就玩一下 你揍他啊
Can I have a go？Can I have a go？You do it！
你好差劲 今天的这个会议电话⋯
Please？No，you！
拜托 就让我快快地玩一盘
Please，just one quick go。Ow！
麦克斯 你马上给我收拾这堆东西
Max，clean up all this crap right now。Sorry，Dad.
对不起 爸爸 我竟然踩了乐高玩具
I just stepped on a Lego.
世界上最让人心痛的事
It's the most painful thing in the world.
我就要赢了
I'm winning over here.
低压系统⋯
我知道我们的航班是取消后重新预订的
I understand that our flight was canceled and rebooked.
客户支持
暴风雪 预告
现在我的问题是 你们把我的家人分到了两个航班上
No，my problem is that you have split our family onto two separate flights.
抱歉 你能大声点吗 这里很吵
I'm sorry，can you speak up，please？It's very loud in here.
你抓不到我 笨蛋
You can never catch me。Jerk！
别碰我 变态 我是你姐姐
Don't touch me，perv。I'm your sister.
居家小精灵 现在是日本的什么年
Homebot，what year is it in Japan？
孩子们 是谁总是把小精灵切换成德语的
Guys，seriously，who keeps swapping the Homebot to German？
嘿 小精灵 不对
Hey！Homebot，nein！Nein！Ha ha！
孩子们 小精灵不是玩具
Guys，Homebot is not a toy
不 停下来 住手 小精灵不是玩具
No，no，stop！Stop it！Homebot is not a toy！
我真是受够了这些破事
I'm sick of this bullsh
咕比 说脏话这种事 就不用跟圣诞老人打报告了 对吗
We don't have to tell Santa about that，right，Goobie？
你说话的时候大声点
You need to project when you speak.
先生 我没有你大呼小叫 妈妈
Sir，I am not taking a tone with you。Mum.
我只是说 你把我的孩子安排到了另一个航班上
I'm simply saying that you have put me on a different flight to my children.
妈妈 电脑不允许更改？
Mum。The computer won't let you？
电脑算什么东西 它是上帝吗
What is the computer？Is it God？Guys，guys
妈妈 等着吧 看我不打你们的屁股
Mum。Mum！Guess what？Spanking's on the menu！
麦克斯 拜托 你以为家里就你一个人 什么都得围着你转吗
Max，please！You are not the only person in this house，darling.
真希望家里就我一个人
I wish I was.
孩子们 别让我追着跑 我有腱炎
Boys，don't make me run。I have tendinitis.
让开 麦克斯
Move，Max.
把手放下来 美式披萨 快来
Lay down your arms！Americans，please！
是披萨 太好了 有多少个披萨
Pizza！Lovely。How many do you have？
三个意大利辣香肠和三个菠萝披萨
Three pepperonis and three pineapples.
那就快吃吧 大家都爱吃菠萝披萨
Let's just get Everybody loves pineapple.
我还要收拾行李和洗衣服
I've still gotta do some packing and some laundry.
大伙儿 吃披萨啦
Everybody，pizza！
大家快过来吃 快点 我们明天早上五点就得起床了
Can you come and eat，please？Seriously。We're gonna be up at 5：00 a.m.
住手
Stop，please！
停 你们会弄断脖子的 看看你们的手提箱
Stop。You'll break your neck。And look at your suitcases.
宝马
机场将出现大面积航班延误
We expect major，major delays at the airport.
天气预警 预计将有更多降雪
不知道奥黑尔国际机场将会何时恢复正常
We don't know when O'Hare is gonna be able to get back…
你今天怎么回事 为什么要提金属探测器
What was that today？Metal detectors？
怎么了 学校确实配了嘛 抱歉 探测器难道不棒棒的吗
What？They have them。I'm sorry。Is that not 「lit」？
好吧 我们现在是想卖掉房子 杰夫
Okay，we are trying to sell the house，Jeff.
是你说了卖房是唯一的选择
You're the one who said it's our only option，
所以我需要你的配合 好吗
so I need you on my team，okay？
我知道
I know。I know。I just
可今天真的要卖房了 我很不喜欢
Today，it felt real，and I didn't like it.
你以为我喜欢吗
You think I do？
我一直以为我们会在这个房子里终老一生
I always thought we'd get old and weird in this house.
可我们算过了 光靠我的工资我们住不起这栋房子
We've done the math。We can't afford it on my salary alone.
对 但我在IBM公司的面试中表现得很好
Yeah，but I crushed my interview with IBM.
表现很好吗 表现很好！
You crushed it。Crushed it！
那已经是三个月之前的事了
But that was three months ago.
凡是有头脑的公司 都会需要优秀的数据迁移经理的 好吗
Any company with a brain needs a good data migration manager，okay？
我是绝对不会在无人监管的情况下
I wouldn't trust an algorithm to port over a MySQL database
靠算法将MYSOL数据库 迁移到新的服务器上的
to a new server without any human oversight.
我也不会 但你可能要过一段时间才能找到新工作
Me neither。But it might take a while to find another job.
你自己也说过 数据迁移的热潮已经过了
You said it yourself。The data migration boom is over.
现在是云时代
It's the cloud.
云时代
The cloud.
反正我需要你的配合 好吗
So I need you to get on board，okay？
高兴一点 这是我们在这里度过的最后一个圣诞节
Come on。It's our last Christmas here.
努力享受节日欢乐吧
Let's try to enjoy it.
无限的欢乐
Tons of fun.
汉特
喂 汉特
Hunter？
帕姆莎啦啦啦啦 有惊喜 我们到你们家外面了
Hey，Pamalamadingdong！Guess what？We're outside！
起床 饶舌皇后奎因·拉蒂法
Get up。Queen Latifah.
起床 你弟弟到了
Get up。Your brother's here.
天啊
God.
该死
Damn it.
天啊 我好想念雪啊
Gosh，I miss the snow！
嘿 你怎么会 怎么会在这里吗
Hey。What are you doing Doing here？
我们早早就乘飞机了 要避开暴雪浩劫嘛
We flew in early to get ahead of snowpocalypse or whatever.
暴雪天劫
Snowmageddon.
暴雪浩劫好一点
Snowpocalypse is better.
宝贝 快来啊
Hey，babe。Hurry up.
来了 宝贝 那是谁
Coming，baby！Who's that？Aah.
帕啷个帕姆 来抱一个
Pamuel L。Jackson！Bring it in.
嗨 汉特
Hi，Hunter。Hi.
她来啦
Here she is！
小心哦
Oh。Careful.
好啦
Okay！Hey。Oh！
我们应该先打电话的 但我们想着给你们惊喜比较好玩
Oh，we would've called，but we thought it would be fun to surprise you.
是啊 你们惊喜吗
Yeah。Are you surprised？
我们很“惊喜” 非常“惊喜”
We are surprised。We're very surprised.
我就知道 这里真美
I know。It's so cute here.
梅婶婶 嗨
Aunt Mei！So quaintHi！
你好 我的宝贝
Hi，my adorables.
我以为你们要明天才到
I didn't think you were coming till tomorrow.
我已经到咯
I'm here now.
我们都以为她明天才到 结果她半夜就到了
We all thought she was coming tomorrow，but she's come in the dead of night.
嗨 奥利 看看是谁来了
Hey，Ollie，look who it is.
是大伯杰夫 嗨 小家伙
It's Uncle Jeff。Hey。Hey，buddy！
奥利 看 是雪 好的
Ollie，look！Snow！
很高兴见到你 小家伙
Good to see you，buddy.
他都长这么大了
He has gotten so big.
好耶
Okay！
天啊 抱歉
Oh，my gosh，I'm so sorry.
这是最后一次了 我保证 好吗
It's the last one。It's the last one。I promise，okay？
别再扔了
That's enough.
你能帮我把行李搬进去吗 我先把小家伙安顿好
Mind giving our luggage a tuggage？I wanna get that guy situated.
哇
Wow.
对 我们这一年过得很滋润
Yeah，we had a great year.
臂力真不错 小家伙
Oh，great arm，buddy！
奥利 那不是玩具 我来捡
Ollie，that is not a toy。I'll get it.
我们正在教他说西班牙语
We're teaching him Spanish！
我怎么跟你说的 不能拿别人的东西
What did I tell you about taking other people's stuff？
你打算让我们睡哪里 娱乐室的沙发床
Where do you have us set up？Oh，in the den on the pullout.
好吧 娱乐室的沙发床 好的
Okay。In the den on the pullout。Yeah，okay.
杰夫·麦肯齐 数据迁移经理 简历浏览次数
易贝网
哇 那位女士说的是真的
Wow，that lady wasn't kidding.
什么
What？
施耐德人仔 上下颠倒的男孩 价格 二十万美元
罕见制作失误 仅制作十件 上一个售价 二十二万七千美元
怎么回事
怎么回事 去哪儿了
What Where is it？
那个臭小子偷了我的洋娃娃 我妈妈的洋娃娃
That brat kid stole my doll。My mom's doll.
该怎样找到这个孩子
How am I gonna find this kid？
麦克斯韦·约翰·默瑟
Maxwell Johan Mercer.
卡罗尔·埃伦·默瑟
Carol Ellen Mercer.
有办法了
Bingo.
已到达目的地
You have arrived at your destination.
快点上车
Get in the car！
你们得赶快上车 你们都不知道我们晚了多久
You need to get in a car now。We are so late。You have no idea.
打中了 你干嘛要打我
Gotcha！What was that for？
我现在好想哭 不可以
I legit might cry right now。Don't！
这是我带领啦啦队要用的 你这个白痴
I need that for cheerleading，you cretin.
去它个三明治的
Son of a sandwich！
快上车
Get in the car！
我们要赶不上飞机了 大伙儿 快点
We're gonna miss the flight，you guys。Come on！
嗨 老兄
Uh，hi，my dude。Um…
卡罗尔·默瑟在吗
Is Carol Mercer home？
卡罗尔乘早班飞机先走了 网约车是她约的
No，Carol took the early flight。She booked the cars.
所以用车人写的是她 但这都是我们约的 我们得出发了
That's why they're in her name。These are our cars。We need to go.
可以麻烦你把行李搬到后备箱吗
Will you be a mensch？Put that in the back for us，huh？Uh…
宝芬妮 现在是在网约车前自拍的时候吗
Bethany，is this a good time for a selfie in front of an Uber？
你这叫“不分场合”
ill judged.
记得发给我 好了 大伙儿 快上车
Text that to me。Okay，guys，get in the car！
把你们的行李都交给司机
Give your stuff to the driver.
要是我赶不及逛免税店… 我不是司机
If I miss the dutyfree shop… I'm not the driver.
我就剃了某人的头 我是说真的
…I am going to shave somebody's head。That's real.
布莱克 你知不知道 在日本能买酒喝
Blake，you do realize they sell alcohol in Japan？
好消息 斯图
Hey，big news，Stu.
免税店里卖将近一米长的三角巧克力
Dutyfree shops sell threefoot Toblerones.
这位兄弟 我把这个交给你了 请你一定要好好看管
Hey，buddy。I'm gonna give that to you and ask you to take real good care of it.
里面装着我的睡眠呼吸机
It's got my sleep apnea machine in there.
你知不知道 卡尔罗的儿子麦克斯在不在家
Do you know if Carol's son，Max，is home？
如果你没看到他的话 那他就是在去日本的路上了
If you don't see him，he's halfway to Tokyo by now。All right.
大家都上车了吗 要开车咯
Is that everyone？The cars are leaving now.
大家一起来 说茄子
Everybody，say cheese.
帕姆 你去哪里了 我们还要为老年人唱歌呢
Everybody，wave.
我出来买牛奶了
全脂牛奶
住这儿的人 密码是什么
Somebody that lives here，what's the code？
你妈妈 谢谢 瑞奇
Your mamma！Thank you，Ricky！
猜猜我要先剃谁的头
Guess who's number one to get his head shaved？
是瑞奇 快说密码
It's Ricky！Code！
1112 1112 太好了
One，one，one，two。One，one，one，two。Brilliant.
这密码太弱了
That's a bad code.
防护已启动
Armed.
搞定 好了
Here we go。All right.
抱歉 但我真的要跟卡罗尔谈谈
I'm sorry，but I really do need to talk to Carol.
好 别担心 我会让卡罗尔在应用上给你五星好评的
Yes。Don't worry。I'll make sure that Carol gives you five stars in the app.
毕竟信誉第一嘛
Reputation is everything.
嘿 等等
Oh，hey，wait！Wait！
你看什么看
What the heck are you looking at？
抱歉 我今天过得太糟糕了
I'm sorry。I'm having a bad day.
在那里
There it is.
天啊
Oh，my…
好吧 是一只狗而已
Okay，it's just a dog.
我太荒唐了 我这是疯了
I'm being ridiculous。I've gone insane.
我是守法好公民 我要告诉帕姆
I'm a good，normal man。I'm gonna talk to Pam.
帕姆
Pam.
我只是来帮忙的邻居
I'm just a neighbor helping.
我浇了他们的狗 不对 是浇了植物
I water their dogsplants.
我是卡罗尔的朋友 她的全名叫卡罗尔·埃伦·默瑟
I'm a friend of Carol's。A friend of Carol Ellen Mercer is her name.
我得打电话给帕姆
I gotta call Pam.
罗斯蒙特 护理及康复中心
他人呢
Where is he？
我不知道他在哪里
I'm not sure where he is.
还好还好
Oh，great.
抱歉
I'm sorry。Sorry.
我来了 抱歉 你还好吗
Oh。Here we go。Sorry。Hi。Is everything okay？
很好 谢谢 你穿的是什么
Yeah，fine。Thank you。What are you wearing？
我没时间换衣服了 你这样穿很搞笑
I didn't have time to change。You look ridiculous.
谢谢 圣诞节快乐 各位长辈
Thank you。Season's greetings，seniors.
很抱歉演唱延迟了 至于为什么延迟 大家都看到了
I apologize for the delay，but we all saw the reason why.
负责降D调的人 让这个世界都按他的时间转
My Dflat has decided that the world runs on his time.
事不宜迟 我们这就给大家呈现 “游手好铃”乐团的表演
Without further ado，I give you the Ne'erDoBells.
手握铃铛
Hands on bells.
举起铃铛
Raise the bells.
二 三 四
Two，three，four.
你收到我的语音邮件了吗 收到了
So did you get my voice mail？Yes.
这都是过去两个小时发生的事情吗
All of this happened in the last two hours？
对 洋娃娃就在那栋房子里 我在他的夹克里看到了
Yeah，the doll is in that house。I saw it in his jacket.
你怎么不跟我说 我以为我可以自己处理
Why didn't you tell me this？I thought I would handle it myself.
你的处理方式就是擅闯民宅吗
And your way of handling it was breaking and entering？
我是正常进入 我有钥匙
Just entering。I had the key.
这依然是违法的 杰夫 像一个灯泡
It's still against the law，Jeff。Like a lightbulb.
天啊 这真是太糟糕了
Oh，my gosh。This is so terrible.
所有其它的驯鹿
所以我没有进去 警官
But that's why I didn't do it，Columbo.
很好
Well，good.
就像匹诺曹 匹诺曹
Like Pinocchio。Pinocchio.
我们该怎么办 我们需要那个娃娃
What are we gonna do now？We need that doll.
我知道 让我想想
I know we do，okay？Just let me think.
加入它们任何的游戏
像专制的霸王 对
Uh，like Monopoly！Yeah.
唱晚了
That's too late。Yeah.
唱得乱七八糟
Boo。Sounds like garbage.
赫尔曼 不能这样说哦 这是实话
Herman，no。None of that。Well，it does.
你们真差劲
You stink.
圣诞老人过来说
我们这么办
Here's what we're gonna do.
我们等他们度假回来
We will wait until they come back from vacation，
我去找他们 我把一切都告诉那个妈妈
and then I will go over there。I will tell the mom everything，
然后我们把娃娃要回来
and we'll get the doll back.
你们要一起唱
Get it together.
你确定我们应该等吗
Are you sure we should wait？
对 杰夫 我不想让我的丈夫在监狱里过圣诞节
Yes，Jeff。I don't want my husband spending Christmas in jail.
好耶 嘿
Yippee！Hey！
哇
Wow.
但是 那房子里藏的是我们的未来 帕姆
But the Our future is in that house，Pam.
放心吧 它在一栋空房子里能出什么事
Come on。What could happen to it in an empty house？
没事的啦 玛莎
It's okay，Martha.
别怪她 出错的是你
Don't blame her。That's you.
抱歉
Sorry.
真可耻 这可是我的人生大事
Shame on you。This is my life choice.
人呢
Hello？
妈妈？
Mum？
爸爸？
Dad？
布莱克叔叔？
Uncle Blake？
斯图叔叔？
Uncle Stu？
圣诞奇迹降临了
It's a Christmas miracle.
加油啊 老兄
Oh，come on，mate！
天啊 隐私！《凯蒂的日记》
好了 互联网 让我看看你的邪恶吧
All right，Internet。Show me your worst.
您的互联网访问受阻
这招厉害 爸爸妈妈
Well played，Mum and Dad.
温内特卡 圣诞集市
帕姆 那个娃娃值二十三万八千美元
Pam，that doll is worth $238，000，
拿回别人从我们家偷走的东西真的违法吗
and is it really a crime to steal something that was stolen from you？
对 橄榄球员辛普森 第二次就是这么惹火上身的
Yes，that's what O.J。got in trouble for。The second time.
好吧 我只是觉得 我知道你想挽救局面
Okay，I just think Look，I know that you wanna save the day
因为你对丢了工作感到很抱歉
because you feel bad about losing your job.
拿回自己的东西有什么错
What's wrong with that？
要是你告诉孩子 你因为犯了重罪而入狱
The fact that you will feel a lot worse telling your kids you're…
你会感觉非常糟糕的
in jail for committing a felony.
不 那只算是轻罪 我查过了
No，it's a misdemeanor。Yeah，I looked it up.
这可是犯罪证据 你知道怎么清除搜索历史吗
That is evidence。Do you know how to clear your search history？
会啊 我应该…
Yeah。I mean，well，I probably
我一定能搞定的 听着
II'm sure I could figure it out。Okay，listen.
我们制定了计划 就按计划行事 好吗
We made a plan。Let's just stick to it，okay？
Mom，Dad，look at us。Hey！
妈妈 爸爸 看我们 嘿
Hey！You like 'em？Look at Ollie.
喜欢吗 看奥利 他是小精灵
He's a little elf.
他真聪明 我们把饰品给他 他就自己戴上了
He's so smart。We handed 'em to him。He put 'em right on.
真聪明
Oh，amazing.
给帕姆来一对驯鹿角
Um，could I get some，uh，reindeer antlers for Pam
再给我哥哥来一副精灵眼镜
and a pair of the little elf glasses for my brother？
圣诞老人屋
奥利 你要笑得灿烂点 好吗
Ollie，we need big smiles from you，okay？Look at Mommy.
咧嘴笑 奥利 咧嘴大笑
Big smiles，Ollie。Big smiles.
这小家伙一面对镜头就激动
Little guy comes alive in front of the camera.
好的 照片很可爱吧
Um，okay，cute photo much？
来 你们看看
I mean，come on。Look at that.
看看拍出的效果 多可爱的画面啊
Look at what's happened there。It's an adorable image.
很可爱 超级可爱
It's cute。It's super cute.
这是特别的回忆
It's a special memory.
因为我们在北极实行无纸化政策
And since we are paperfree at the North Pole，
你们可以使用这个密码
you can actually use this code
在云端下载这些特别的回忆照
to download that special memory right from the cloud.
所以你们现场连固态储存也没有吗
WhSo，you're not even using solidstate storage onsite？
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what that means.
那我来告诉你
I'll tell you what it means.
你们把虚拟化和备份 全部交给托管服务提供商来负责
What it means is，you're entirely at the whim of a hosted service provider
这是很危险的
for virtualization and backup.
先生 我不是技术行业人士
Sir，I'm not a woman in tech.
我只制造美好回忆 这不是电子游戏
I'm a woman in memories。You know，it's not a video game.
她不在乎这个 我搞不明白
She doesn't care。I don't understand
你们为什么会对这么重要的事情不上心
why you'd be so cavalier with something this important.
玛蒂娜服装
What is this？
这是新时尚 宝贝 我们换一下颜色
New fashion，honey。We gotta We gotta switch up these colors.
妈妈 看这条裙子多漂亮
Mom，look at how cute this is。So cute.
真漂亮 我可以买吗
Can I get it？Oh.
不行 宝贝 很抱歉 这太贵了
Oh，honey，no。I'm sorry，that's way too much.
不行 我不能让你错过这条裙子
Okay，no，no，no。I can't stand the thought of you not having that.
就当这是梅梅婶婶提前给你送的圣诞礼物
Consider it an early Christmas present from Auntie MeiMei.
你穿起来一定很漂亮 来
You're gonna look so hot。Come on.
梅⋯ 你说真的吗
Mei。Are you kidding？
买这件
This，please.
加文（房产经纪人） 给我打电话 我有一些好消息
A top for you.
我告诉你我要送你什么 斯内克斯
I'll tell you what I am gonna give you，Snakes.
数到十以后
I'm gonna give you 'til the count of ten
我要把你这个丑陋 懦弱 没用的浑蛋
to get your ugly，yellow，nogood keister…
真是垃圾 送下我的飞船
Ugh，this is garbage。…off my spaceship…
真搞不懂为什么他们总是要重拍经典
I don't know why they're always trying to remake the classics.
重拍的永远比不上原版
Never as good as the originals.
要吃爆哩个米花吗 克哩个斯
You want some more Pcorn，CTrain？
好啊 那就太好了 好的
Oh，yeah，that'd be great。All right.
我不记得家里有这个呀
One，two… I don't remember this guy.
你们的房子差点就没了 帕姆莎啦啦啦啦
Nearly lost your house there，Pamalamadingdong.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey，honey.
把顶饰装上吧 我们一起好吗
Put the topper on。Should we put it on together？
好 一 二
Yeah。One，two，three.
圣诞老人来过啦
Santa came！Santa came！
Santa came！Santa came！Santa came！
我好高兴呀
I'm so excited.
圣诞老人来过啦
Santa came！
噢 天啊 圣诞老人来过了
Oh，my God！Santa came.
来抱抱 天啊
Come here。Oh，my God！
甜蜜的家
Home sweet home.
妈妈 你一定要拯救我们的房子
Mom，you gotta save our house.
说真的 妈妈 你可以把娃娃拿回来吗
Seriously，Mom，will you just get the doll？
我们是正常入室 帕姆 我们有钥匙
It's just entering，Pam。We have the key.
帕姆 快给我打电话
Pam，you have to call me.
嗨 加文… 来把我带回去
Hi，Gavin… Come and get me.
快来 女士
Now，Fräulein。Now！
我会的 你这丑丑的小男孩
I will，you ugly，little boy！
不用找零钱了 你这肮脏的俗人
Keep the change，ya filthy earthling.
我倒是觉得你很帅气
Well，I think you're very handsome.
我们走
Let's go.
去哪里 去买牛奶
Where are we going？To get some milk.
冰箱里还有很多牛奶 帕姆
Oh，well，there's plenty of milk in the fridge，Pammy.
你们有很多牛奶 库存充足得很
No，you guys have a ton of milk。You're all set on milk.
蛋酒 我们要去买些蛋酒
Uh，eggnog。We need We're gonna get some eggnog.
你们看过天气了吧 外面正上演着暴雪天劫
You've seen the weather，right？It's snowmageddon out there.
是暴雪浩劫 暴雪浩劫好一点
Yeah，snowpocalypse，babe。Snowpocalypse is better.
你们能开车吗
Are you gonna be okay to drive？Yes，yes，yes，yes.
能开
能开 我们当然能开
Yes。We are okay to drive.
亲爱的 你的直觉是对的
Honey，your instincts were right.
我们不能把发财的宝贝放在陌生人的家里
We can't leave a winning lottery ticket in some stranger's house.
对 我们这就去拿
Yeah，yeah。We are doing this.
亲爱的 那就是山毛榉街
Oh，honey，that's Beechtree.
亲爱的 朝滑的方向打方向盘
Honey，steer into the slide.
不 应该说是朝打滑的方向打方向盘
NNo，yyou steer into a skid.
帕姆 我今天点播了一集《面对面》
Pam，I watched an episode of Locked Up earlier today on demand，
我不能进监狱 帕姆
and… I can't go to jail，honey.
我在普犯里绝对撑不了30秒
I wouldn't last 30 seconds in gen pop.
什么普犯
Gen pop？
普通犯人 新囚犯会被抓起来打
General population。It's where fresh fish get got.
杰夫
Jeff.
给我打起精神来
I need you to focus.
我们谁也不会被抓起来打
Nobody here is getting got.
我们唯一要抓的是那个瓷娃娃
The only thing getting got is that doll.
现在我们就去抓
So let's go get it！
你能解锁车门吗 好的 抱歉
Can you unlock the door？Yeah。Sorry.
别动
Don't move.
为什么站着不动
Why are we standing still？
因为灯光是动态感应式的 我们站着不动的话 它就会熄灭
Because the light is motionactivated，and if we stand still，it'll turn off.
但只要我们继续走动 灯就会再亮起来
Yeah，but it's just gonna turn back on when we move again.
所以我们为什么要站着不动
So，why are we standing still now？
我不知道 我不擅长这个嘛
I don't know。I'm not good at this.
我知道
I know.
我们现在是罪犯了 快进去
And we're criminals.
大门开启
Go.
警报
Alarm.
好大声
It's loud.
警报
Alarm.
当心 别滑倒
Be careful。Don't slip.
密码无效
Okay.
他们离开得很匆忙
They did leave in a hurry.
警报启动
你在哪里看见小孩的夹克的 之前就在这里
Where'd you see the kid's jacket？It was right here.
好了 我们试过了
Well，we tried.
夹克又不会长脚 它一定在这里的某个地方
A jacket can't just get up and walk away。It has to be here somewhere.
不要抛下我
Hey，don't bail on me.
我们是一个团队
We're a team.
好的
OOkay.
是他？我就知道他有问题
Him？I knew he was weird.
我们只需要找到那个丑小孩
All we have to do is find that ugly，little boy.
就会有疯老婆子花二十万美元买它
And then some crazy，old lady will pay us $200，000 for him.
花二十万美元 就为了把它放在一个房间里
Twohundred grand just to put him in a room，
用她的小刷子给它做清洁 然后跟她的朋友显摆炫耀
clean him off with her little brushes，and show him off to all her friends.
我可以喂他吃一块恶心的老太太糖吗
May I feed him a piece of this gross，old lady candy？
当然 他就吃这个
Of course。That's all he eats.
格特鲁德 他真好玩
Oh，Gertrude。He's perfect.
这钱花得值
Worth every penny.
花五千买一个丑丑的瓷娃娃
Five grand for an ugly，porcelain kid.
我亲生的娃娃都卖不到一半的价格呢
I didn't get half that for my real kids.
找不到它我们就不走
We're not leaving here without him.
我可不答应
I don't think so.
是那件外套
The jacket.
小精灵 报警
Homebot，call the police.
有人在家
There's someone home.
而且还是德国人
And she's German.
好的 数到三 我们撤 一
Okay，on three，we run。One.
这也太快了
Whoa，that was fast.
温内特卡警察 温内特卡村
麦卡利斯特
晚上好
Evening.
嗨
Hi.
您好 警官
Hello，Officer.
你滑倒了吗
Did somebody slip and fall？
要被抓了吧
Ha！Busted.
这是你们的住处吗
Is this your residence？
不是我们的还能是谁的
Well，I certainly hope so.
要不然我过去14年 不是白白帮别人清理污水坑了吗
Otherwise，I've been cleaning somebody else's sinks for the past 14 years.
污水坑
Sinks.
有什么问题吗 警官
Is there a problem，Officer？
亲爱的 你先去发动汽车吧
Honey，why don't you go warm up the car？
我们接到电话 你们的警报启动了
We got a call。Your home alarm's been triggered.
是啊 密码是我们的纪念日
Yeah，well，the code is our anniversary，so…
您觉得他会记得吗
you think he's gonna remember that？
您肯定不会忘记你们的纪念日 对吧 警官
I'm sure you never forget your anniversary，do you，Officer？
不 不
Oh，no，no.
我的无名指上还没戴戒指呢 夫人
No ring on this finger，ma'am.
还没人能驯服我这狂野的公马
No one's been able to tame this wild stallion.
真羡慕最后能拿下您的小母马
Well，I envy the filly who eventually ropes you in.
在别的时间 别的地点
Another time，another place.
有着很多可能性 警官
A whole lot of whatifs，Officer.
好了 很抱歉浪费了您的时间
Anyway，I'm so sorry we wasted your time.
今晚还有什么需要我配合的吗
Is there anything else I can help you with tonight？
没有 不用担心这个
No，don't worry 'bout it。No.
除非你需要我 以忘记纪念日的名义逮捕你的丈夫
Unless you want me to arrest your husband for missing your anniversary，huh？
要是我说“我确实想这样做”是不是很坏
Is it bad if a part of me says，「Yeah，I do want that」？
是什么这么好笑
What's so funny？
要抓他吗
Get it？
你在等什么 逮捕他们啊
What are you waiting for？Detain them.
那… 逮捕他们
Now Detain them！
什么声音
What was that？
没事 没问题
Nah，nah，we're all good.
祝你和你丈夫节日愉快
What say you and your hubby have a nice holiday.
晚安
And a good night.
等等 你竟然把他们放走了
Wait，you're letting them get away.
然后那两个人闯进我家
AndAnd then those people broke into my house，
我想他们是要绑架我或者…
and III Whoa，whoa.
…think they're trying to kidnap me or Whoa，whoa，whoa，whoa，whoa.
你是说你父母把你单独留在家？
Are you saying your parents left you home alone？
单独留在家？
Alone？Alone？Alone？
你为什么要告诉别人 麦克斯
Why did you have to tell anyone，Max？
你为什么要这么大嘴巴
Why did you have to open your big mouth？
也许报警不是个好主意
Maybe the police is a bad idea.
不错的夫妇
Nice couple.
你知道吗
You know what？
独自在家也许也没那么美妙 小精灵
This whole housetomyself thing might not have been the best idea，Homebot.
你要怎么切换回英语
How do you switch back to English？
将语言更换为英语
Changing language to English.
原来这么简单啊
Oh，that was easy.
小精灵 呼叫妈妈
Homebot，call Mum.
很抱歉 这款小精灵设备没有语言呼叫功能
I'm sorry。Voice calling is not available on this Homebot device.
那我该怎么办 小精灵
So what do I do，Homebot？
我联系不上妈妈 如果我告诉警察或其他人
I can't call my mum，and if I tell the police or anyone else，
他们会让我爸妈进监狱的
they'll put my parents in jail.
蓝鲸的血管很大 可以让成人在里面游泳同行
A blue whale's veins are big enough for an adult human to swim through.
你说这个有什么用
How is that supposed to help？
现在是东京的几点钟
What time is it in Tokyo？
现在是日本东京第二天早上的11点37分
It is 11：37 a.m。tomorrow in Tokyo，Japan.
晚安 小精灵
Night，Homebot.
晚安 麦克斯
Good night，Max.
你说什么
What？
东京皇宫酒店
WhaAre youAre you serious？
你有没有搞错 你就没想过跟我核实吗
So at no point you thought to check with me？
你想当然地认为麦克斯在另一趟航班上？
You just assumed that Max was on the other flight？
我们没有点人数 我…
We didn't take a census。I
斯图 是你猜麦克斯在另一趟航班上的吗
Stu，did you assume he was on the plane？
卡罗尔 我发誓 我们出发时他不在家里
Carol，I swear to you。That boy was not in the house when we left.
那你觉得他当时在哪儿 斯图 在该死的四季酒店里吗
And where do you think he was，Stu？At theAt the Four freaking Seasons？
他在飞机上吃了咖喱鱼
He had fish curry on the plane.
我们估计得等30分钟才能看到他
We probably got a hard 30 before we're gonna see Stu.
你知不知道 就因为你 我在日本
You do realize that，because of you，I'm in Japan，
而我十岁的儿子却单独留在家
and my tentenyearold son is at home by himself？
我知道 但这也不是什么大错吧
Yeah，butbut firstworld problems，you know？
不是什么大错？ 别打
Firstworld problems？Stop it。Listen，listen，stop it！
这是我在品牌店买的
I got that at Brookstone.
爸爸还有五分钟就回来
Dad's five minutes away.
他在旅行服务台那边 只能买到一张回家的票
He's at the travel desk and could only get one ticket home.
喂 您好 山毛榉街道
Yes，hello。Beechtree Lane.
木字旁加举手的举 您可以立刻派一名警察过去吗
With two Beech with two E's。Can you send an officer right away？
有人给家里打电话了吗
Did somebody call the house？
没有 因为家里没装固定电话 现在没人用固定电话
No，because we don't have a landline。Nobody has a landline anymore.
对 斯图 没人用固定电话了 因为现在不是1993年
Yes，Stu，nobody has a landline anymore because it's not 1993.
你还有什么新点子 我是不是应该 听着八九十年代的歌曲 用寻呼机联系他
What's your next idea？Should I beep him after I listen to the new MC Hammer joint？
邻居呢 联系邻居怎么样
What about the neighbors？Call one of the neighbors.
让祷告团开始为他的平安祷告吧 我们不认识邻居 布莱克
Activate the prayer chain。We don't know the neighbors，Blake.
我们才搬进去两个月 我连他们叫什么都不知道
We only moved there two months ago。I don't think we even know their names.
我们认识的人都在伦敦
Everybody we know is back in London.
妈妈 你要去哪里
Well，Mum，where are you going？
我要去机场 我儿子还在家里 我不能坐着干等
I'm going to go to the airport，darling，because I can't sit here while my son is
我真的…我的护照呢
I meanGod，where is my passport？
就在你手上 在我手上
It's in your hand。It's in my hand。It's in my hand.
看吧 卡罗尔 别焦虑 别人犯了错我们要大方原谅
See，Carol？Under stress，people make mistakes that we should forgive.
比如忘了带护照 比如忘了带孩子
You know？People forget passports。People forget
不 别扔
No！Stop it.
宝贝 圣诞节快乐 妈妈非常爱你 好吗
Oh，darling，happy Christmas。Mummy loves you very much。Okay？
现在是什么情况 卡罗尔走了吗
Uh，what's happening？Did Carol leave？
一路平安
Travel safe.
现在是什么情况
WhatWhat's going on？
18号车 你在林肯海茨街区附近吗
Car 18，car 18。You near Lincoln Heights？
我们接到一通电话 有一个叫麦克斯韦·默瑟的小孩
We got a call about a minor，one Maxwell Mercer.
他的父母去度假 可能把他遗忘在家里了
Parents are on vacation and think he might have been left behind.
地址是山毛榉街道36号 你开玩笑吧
Address is 36 Beechtree Lane。Oh，you gotta be kidding me.
Um…
不用管了 这是个恶搞电话 完毕
You can ignore that。That is a prank call。Over.
恶搞电话？ 对
Prank call？Yep.
我小的时候 我们一家去度假
Listen，when I was a kid，my family went on vacation.
但我们把我弟弟凯文遗忘在家里了
We forgot my little brother Kevin.
而且是两次
Twice.
所以他现在会打这种电话捉弄我 那个白痴每年都这么做
He called in the 289 to mess with me。The idiot does it every year.
你确定吗
Are，uh，you sure about that？
我确定得不得了
Yes，I'm sure about that！
我确定那个地址没有小孩被遗忘在家里
I know for a fact that there is no forgotten child at that address.
我刚刚 因为一个假的家居警报去过一趟 好吗
I was just there for a bogus homealarm call，okay？
你知道吗 那家装了麦卡利斯特家居安保系统
Guess what？The place had a McCallister Home Alarm system.
有这么巧的事情吗 我可不认为
Oh，gee，a coincidence？I don't think so.
好吧 你可以顺便开过去看看吗
Yeah。So can you just drive by and check it out？
好吧 我这就过去
Tenfour。I'm on my way now.
这招够狠啊 凯文
Nice try，Kevin。Nice try.
讨厌鬼
Trout sniffer.
你们好
Hey，guys.
我们给你们留了位置 因为你们来晚了
Hey。We saved you some seats 'cause you were running late.
还有人陆续过来呢 嗨
People are still coming in。Hi.
我们给你留了位置 因为你来教堂晚了
Hey，we saved you a seat 'cause you were running late to church.
好 谢谢
Yep。Thanks.
我下载了一款应用 它可以提醒你的助理
I've got an app that will ping your assistant，
让你的助理通知你 你要迟到了 我发给你
let you know when you're running late。I'll send it to you.
好 好的 谢谢
Great。Okay。Thank you.
嘿 那条裙子是不是有点那个
Hey，so that dress is really…
她的肩膀露得也太多了
Her shoulder is so bare。You see the full
整个肩膀都露出来了
You see her full shoulder。Yeah.
孩子长得真快啊 对吧 加文 你怎么也来了
They grow up so fast，don't they？Oh，Gavin。What are you doing here？
今天是圣诞前夕嘛 所以大家都往教堂跑
Well，it's Christmas Eve。It's the day that everybody goes to church.
对吧 对
Am I right？Yeah.
愿您平安 是这么说的吗
Peace be unto you。Peace be unto you。Is that how you say it？Peace be unto
真棒啊
Oh，this is nice.
圣托马斯 天主教堂
教堂玩具募捐 儿童玩具 入内捐赠
你们都在躲着我 这是怎么回事
You dudes have been ghosting me。What up with that？
没有 我们只是… 我有消息了
No，we're But I've got some news.
“指挥中心” 有人报价了
Houston，we have an offer.
什么
What？Um.
有人报价给你爸爸做私人训练
Um，it's an offer for your dad's，uh，personal training.
你已经付了减肚腩的钱
And since you already paid for that jelly belly，
所以我再给你加腹肌和大腿的训练 我们说的是这个
I'm gonna throw in some abs and thighs。That's what that is.
谢谢 很好
Thank you。Great.
克里斯 你把玩具拿到募捐区好吗
Hey，Chris，honey，why don't you go put that，uh，toy in the toydrive area.
我们为你感到骄傲 真的
Yeah，we're so proud of you。We really are.
把礼物送给有需要的孩子 我就是有需要的孩子 我需要这个
Well，I'm definitely a child in need。Need of this.
需要帮助的吗 噢 需要
Can I help you？Oh，yes.
可以给我推一辆购物车过来吗
Can I get a shopping cart，please？
购物车？
Mmm？Shopping cart.
不 宝贝
No，sweetheart.
这些玩具是送给没你这么幸运的孩子的
These toys are for children less fortunate than you.
好吧 我就说哪有这种好事
Ah，okay。Thought it was too good to be true.
好酷
Whoa，cool.
谢谢 小绅士
Thank you，young man.
祝你们都有个快乐的圣诞节
And I hope you both have a very，very happy Christmas.
这是不可能的了 为什么 怎么了 是父母出问题了吗
That's unlikely。Why？What's wrong？Parent trouble？
对
Yeah.
跟我说说
Tell me about it.
他们以为我不知道他们有压力
They think I don't notice that they're stressed，
但他们太明显了
but it's super obvious.
有一个怪怪的人总是冒出来 假装他是私人教练
Some weird guy keeps showing up pretending to be a personal trainer.
怎么样 你们有什么想法
So？What do you say？
是谁出的价 布莱克金夫妇
WhatWhoWho made this offer？Oh，the Breckins.
还记得从市里来的那对年轻夫妇吗
Remember the young couple from the city？
他们想在新年前签好合同
Yeah，so they need to sign the contract before the new year.
以便应对税的问题
Something about a tax thing.
不可能 这不可能
We can't do that。That's impossible.
他们还真有钱 对吧 我们才是最穷的
Yeah，rich people。Am I right？We're the worst.
但听着 除这个以外不会有更高的报价了
But listen，we're not gonna get a better offer than this.
所以你们趁着过节好好想想 然后回复我
So，why don't you take the holiday，think it over and get back to me.
好吗 不要有压力 好吧 还是有点压力的
All right？No presh。Well，maybe a little presh.
好吧 其实压力很大
All right，you know，it's a lot of presh，actually.
好了 圣诞节快乐
All right，cool。Merry Christmas.
我可以给你们发一下名片吗
You know what？Can I give you a couple of my business cards？
我叫加文·华盛顿 我是房产经纪人
Yeah。Gavin Washington。I do real estate.
至少你爸爸妈妈都在你身边
At least you're with your mum and dad.
我爸爸妈妈去了东京 我完全是一个人
Mine have gone to Tokyo。I'm totally on my own.
这也太酷了吧
That's the coolest thing ever.
我本来也以为很酷 但也只酷了一个小时
I thought it would be，and for about an hour，it was.
现在我好孤独
But now I'm just lonely.
来 送给你
Here。Have this.
听起来你和其它的孩子一样需要它
Sounds like you deserve it as much as anybody.
圣诞节快乐 你也是
Merry Christmas。You too.
和家人开心地过圣诞节吧 这才是圣诞节的特殊魅力
Enjoy it with your family。That's what makes it special.
这小子真好
Nice kid.
谢谢 你真是善良的小男孩
Thank you。You're a kind little boy.
不管你今年想要什么 圣诞老人一定会让你心想事成的
I think that Santa's gonna bring you everything you want this year.
那就太好了 不过说真的
That'd be nice，but to be honest，
我只想要我的爸爸妈妈回来
all I really want is my mum and dad back.
天啊 你的爸爸妈妈都“走”了吗
Oh，dear。Well，when did you lose them？
两天前走的
Um，two days ago.
竟然是在圣诞期间“走”的 可怜的孩子
Oh。Right at Christmas？You poor little thing.
那么谁来照顾你
But who's taking care of you？
家里就只有我和咕比 不过我们撑过来了
Uh，it's just me and Goobie at home，but we're getting by all right.
我因锡安必不静默
For Zion's sake，I will not keep silent…
帕姆 是那个孩子
Pam。Pam，it's the kid.
没错 是他 那个老太太是谁
You're right。It is。Who's the old lady？
她的救赎⋯ 看房日那天 那孩子的妈妈说
Oh，at the open house，the kid's mom said
她会把孩子留下来跟他奶奶一起过
she was gonna leave the kid behind with the grandmother.
没想到她会真的这么干
I can't believe she went through with that.
所以那个说德语的是他奶奶
So grandma's the German.
说德语的是他奶奶
Grandma's the German.
好的 现在有什么计划
All right。So what's the plan？
时机完美 我们趁他们不在家时把瓷娃娃要回来
It's perfect。We go now while they're not home and get our doll back.
老太太开车慢 我们在他们出停车场之前进屋拿东西离开
The way old ladies drive，we'll be in and out before they leave the parking lot.
减速
哇 我得经常来教堂了
Wow，I need to come to church more often.
现在街上人太多了
The street's too hot right now.
我们等到天黑再动手
We'll wait till it gets dark.
我们待会儿再回来
We'll go around back.
遵命 帕姆警官
Okay，Axel Foley.
候补
Standby…
Standby.
抱歉 刚刚她是说了“候补”吗
Sorry，did you just hear standstandby？Huh？
抱歉 借过一下 抱歉
Sorry，sorry，sorry。Excuse me，excuse me，excuse me。Sorry，sorry，sorry，sorry.
Um…
抱歉 你好
Sorry，uh，sorry。Uh，konnichiwa.
请问你们什么时候
When will the the standthe standby seats，
宣布候补席位 什么时候
um，be announced？When？
宣布
AAnnounced？
女士 我非常乐意为您效劳 但请您先排队
Ma'am，I'd be more than happy to help you after you stand in the line behind you.
谢谢 节日快乐
Thank you，and happy season.
我急着回家陪我的儿子
I am trying to get home to my son，
他独自一人 担惊受怕 他需要妈妈
who's alone and scared，and he needs his mother.
所以我要你现在就回答我的问题
So I need you to answer my question right now.
候补席位将会在登记窗口关闭后宣布
Standby seat assignments will be announced after the checkin window closes
大概在起飞前的一小时
approximately one hour before departure.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有 抱歉
And sorry.
抱歉
不客气 感谢选择我们的航班
Oh，not a problem。Thank you for flying with us.
您好
Hi.
要动手了吗
So we're doing this？
对 表现自然点
Yeah，just act casual.
就假装是在散步 对
Just going for a walk。Yeah.
我们只不过是在晚上 散步到了别人家的后院
It's just a stroll through people's backyards aat night.
还散步到了灌木丛里
Through some undergrowth.
这是世界上最正常不过的事情了 对
It's the most natural thing in the world。Yeah.
你知道要怎么走吗
Do you know where you're going？
知道 跟我来
Yes。Now follow me.
你将在耶和华的手中成为华冠
…you shall be a crown of beauty in the hands of the Lord.
他们去哪里了
Hey，where are they？
“忘记预热烤炉了 很快就回来”
「Forgot to preheat the oven。Be back soon.」
这需要两个人回去吗
That's a twoperson job？I don't know.
看 要开始了
Shh。Oh，look。It's starting.
开始了
Oh，here we go.
快看艾比 她真漂亮
Oh，look at Abby。She looks so good.
噢 神圣的夜晚
星星在明亮地闪耀
这样的夜晚
就是这样
This is it.
正是亲爱的救世主的诞生之夜
这院墙怎么砌得这么高
Why's the wall so high？
他们当这里是白金汉宫吗
It's not like it's Buckingham Palace.
好的 我们这样
Okay。Here's what we'll do.
我把你抬上去 你上去后再拉我一把
I'm gonna boost you up，and then when you get to the top，you'll lift me up.
你可以做到吗 可以
Do you think you can do that？Yeah.
好的
Okay.
Okay，okay.
好 准备好了吗
Okay。Ready？
好了
Okay.
屈膝跪下
聆听天使的声音
Just Whoa！Just Ow！
好的 你就…
Okay。Just
一 二
One，two.
天啊 抱歉
Oh，my God。I'm sorry。I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
快爬上去
Just get up there.
好 三
Okay。Three.
你拉着我爬上来 好
Now climb up me。Okay.
基督就是上主
抓住我的手
Take my hand.
他的力量
上去
Get up there.
和光辉
我们永远歌颂
好
Okay.
我快上来了
I'm nearly up.
他的力量
和光辉
我们永远歌颂
好了 帕姆 我…
It's okay，Pam。I
有门
Oh.
A gate.
这里竟然有侧门
A side gate？Really？
抱歉 但你不是也没看见侧门嘛
I'm sorry，but it's not like you saw the gate either.
对了 我很好 谢谢
Oh，I'mI'm fine by the way。Thank you.
走吧
Come on.
什么
What？
是我们的女儿
That's our little girl.
试着开门 好的
Try the door。Okay.
“区别在于 衣服是为你量身定做的”
「…the difference being that the clothes are made to fit you，
“但你必须为树而定制”
while you have to be made to fit the tree.「
最好不要让你爸爸听到你这么说
Better not let your father hear you say that.
好的
Okay，Mom.
“想要用他们的水桶”
「…wanted to with their buckets.
“他们多么热切地爱着…”
And how ardently they grew to love their…「
走错房子了 怪我 我也以为是那里
The wrong house。That's on me。Yeah，yeah。I get the sense it was.
我们去下一家
Okay，let's just go next door.
他肯定在那家 我们去看看
That's where he lives。We're gonna check it out.
我们踩到了泳池上
We're in a swimming pool！
好冷啊
We're freezing！
我拉你起来 过来
Pulling you up！Come here！
快来
Come on！
爬到我的背上
What should I do？Get on my back！
“他们飞向梦幻岛”
「…one step，they leapt into the sky toward Neverland.」
为什么先生和女士要淹在水里
Why are man and lady drowning？
不 他们不是淹在水里 是飞在天上
No。They're not drowning。They're in the sky flying.
好的 我上来了 好了
Okay。I'm up。I'm up。Okay.
游到我这里来
Swim。Swim to me.
我拉你
I got you.
我拉你 过来
Pull you up。Come here.
你上来了
And you're out.
我们这是在干什么
What are we doing？
我是老师 你是数据…
I am a teacher.
You're a data…
迁移经理 经理
…manager。Migration manager.
也许是老天在告诫我们
Maybe the universe is trying to tell us something，you know？
也许我们应该接受瓷娃娃弄丢了的事实
I mean，maybe we should just cut our losses.
不
No.
我们不能放弃
We're not giving up.
我们必须要CG 帕姆
We need a W，Pam.
成功
A win.
对
Yeah.
那本来就是我们的
We do deserve a W.
我们是好人 帕姆
We're good people，Pam.
就因为那个英国臭小子
And we're gonna lose our home because Harry stinkin' Potter
到我们家偷走了我们的救星 所以我们就要失去房子
comes into our house and steals the only thing that can fix our problems.
不 没有这种道理
No。That's an injustice.
对 那不公平
Yeah。That's not fair.
如果我们现在就放弃 那我们算什么
AndAnd who are we if we give up now？I mean，what do we say to our kids？
我们要怎么跟孩子们说
“对不起 我们毁了你们的生活”
「Oh，sorry we flushed your life down the toilet，
“但生活不断地用爱偷东西的小孩”
but life kept smacking us down with klepto kids
“说德语的奶奶和愚蠢的云来击垮我们”
and German grandmothers and the stupid cloud.「
我恨你 云
I hate you，cloud.
我们受够了
Enough is enough.
我们的希望 我们家的希望都在那房子里 我们要拿回我们的希望
Our W，our family's W，is in that house，and we're gonna get it.
现在就去
Right now.
现在可能不太合适
Well，I don't know about right now。Becau
他们随时都会到家
I mean，they could come home at any second.
而且 我的裤子开始冻硬了
Also，my pants are starting to freeze.
我的也是
Oh，mine too.
我的腿已经完全没知觉了
Like，I don't feel that.
At all.
那就晚点再来
So let's come back later，you know？Like after dinner，after bbedtime even.
比如吃晚饭后 甚至是等到入睡时间后
或者午夜 好吗 等老太太睡了再来
Midnight，you know？Like after after the old lady's gone to sleep.
但如果那个孩子醒了怎么办
Yeah，but what if the kid wakes up？
孩子们总是
You know，kids are always running down
要熬到深夜 看圣诞老人是不是来了
in the middle of the night to see if Santa came.
如果我假扮成圣诞老人怎么样
What if I dress as Santa？
他会觉得我是来送礼物的圣诞老人
He'll think I'm just Saint Nick.
但我这个圣诞老人
But this Santa's gonna be leaving
会把那个价值二十万美元的丑娃娃 装到袋子里带走
with that $200，000 ugly little boy in his sack.
这样我们就成功了
And that's how we win.
好的 那就午夜再来 圣诞老人先生
Okay。Midnight it is，Mr。Claus.
X消灭者ZL3 水枪
准备好战斗了吗
我才不要被抓到某个老太太家
I'm not spending my best years in some old lady's bedroom.
小精灵 搜索厉害的陷阱
Homebot，search good booby traps.
抱歉 本系统的家长限制系统 限制搜索词汇“遗骸”
I'm sorry，the parental controls of this system restrict the term 「booby.」
算了
Never mind.
我喜欢你的裙子 奥利 那是什么
I love this dress。Ollie，Ollie，what is that？
这是你从教堂里拿的吗
Hey，did you take that from the church？Oh？
什么…
What
妈妈 爸爸 你们去哪里了
Mom，Dad，where were you？
发生什么事了
And whawhat happened？
有辆车经过一个水坑 把我们都溅湿了
A car drove through a puddle and splashed us.
很讨厌 想象一下
What is。Yuck。Imagine that.
我们得准备晚餐了 对吗
Well，we should get dinner ready，huh？
对
Yeah.
泛日本航空
10小时11分后抵达 东京成田机场 芝加哥奥尔黑国际机场
抱歉 我看你的屏幕了吗
Sorry。Am I looking at your screen？
Yes。Oh，okay.
对 好吧
我看的时候没意识到
Yes。I didn't even realize I'm doing it.
很正常 是啊
Classic。Yeah.
你又看了 我又看了吗
Sorry，you're doing it again。I'm still doing it？
对 我就是控制不住
Yes。I justI just can't help it，you know？
这是我的屏幕 那是你的
This is my screen，and that's your screen，so…
我知道 我知道怎么操作 好的
No，I know that。I know how screens work。Yeah.
屏幕里其实有电视节目和电影 你懂吧
You know they got TV and films on there？
我懂 我非常懂 我只是急着想回家
Yep，yep，fully aware。I'm just，um，eager to get home.
你这就像盯着一个烧水壶 你盯它水也不能加快烧开
It's like watching a watched pot，though。It's not gonna boil.
总会烧开的
Yeah，well，it might one day.
好的
Okay.
我睡一会儿 谢谢
I'll just get some sleep。Thank you.
你要盖我的毯子吗 不要
Would you like some of my blanket？Okay。No.
10小时09分钟后抵达
抱歉 很抱歉 我接受你的道歉了
Sorry。I'm sorry。Apology accepted.
今年梅本来想在夏威夷过圣诞节的
So，Mei wanted to spend Christmas in Hawaii this year，
但我让她打消这个心思 来这里过节
but I told her，we just gotta suck it up and come here
因为我知道你们会喜欢的
because I knew you guys would appreciate it.
《牛津德语迷你字典》
作战计划
可乐 飞镖球
点火液
他可以当模特 他只有…
He could be a model，and he's only
你几岁了 四岁
How old are you？Four，right？Like a runway model？
比如走秀模特吗
什么模特都行 他们说他这个年纪 能有这种身材非常了不得
Any kind of model。They say he has an incredible body for a boy his age.
撒旦屁屁 核武器级辣酱
圣诞时光 充满欢乐
但活在恐惧中的孩子却没有欢乐
问题不在于不幸的男孩和女孩
得不到礼物和玩具
黄油
在充满饥饿和战争的世界
我们都需要圣诞老人的安慰
拿着 给孩子的 克里斯
Here you go。Just for the kids。Chris.
手表
No.
不
这还不是我们给你们买的最贵的礼物哦
That's not the most expensive thing we bought you.
我们不能收 谢谢
We can't keep those。Thank you.
曼妥思薄荷糖
看那两个温暖的小精灵 已经躺下了
Oh，look at those snuggly，little elves all ready for bed.
还有半个小时就到圣诞节了 明天早上见
Only a halfhour left till Christmas。See you in the morning.
子弹上膛 准备战斗
Locked and loaded.
好了 我有个计划
Okay，we have a plan.
如果按计划行事 我们就能神不知鬼不觉地完成任务
If we stick to it，we'll be back before anyone will even notice.
亲爱的 慢点
Honey，slow down.
Babe，slow down.
我在减速了 但路太滑了
I'm trying。It's so icy.
踩刹车呀
Put on the brakes！
朝滑的方向打方向盘 不对
Steer into the slide。No.
遇到打滑时 是超打滑的方向打方向盘
You pump into a slide，and you steer into a skid.
到底哪个是对的 我不知道
Which one is this？I'm not sure.
耶
Yes.
好了 好了 逃过一劫
Okay。Okay。It's all over.
本来结果会更严重的
Could've been worse。Could've Yeah.
好了 忘掉这次的不顺利 打起精神
Okay。Let's shake that off and focus.
我们来了
We are doing this.
We are doing it.
我们速战速决…
We'll be in and out before you
看来是没法顺利了
This is not going well.
我好像摔坏尾椎了
I think I shattered my coccyx.
当心点 杰夫 这里很滑
Be careful，Jeff。It's slippery.
是吗 谢谢“提醒”了
Oh，really？Thanks for letting me know.
我好像找到诀窍了
I think I've worked out a good method.
你怎么样
How are you doing？
很好 我在慢慢过去 我能行的
Good。I'm getting there.
I'm gonna make it.
好的 我来了
All right。I'm doing this.
我跟着你 亲爱的 再走一步就成功了
I'm right behind you，babe。One more step and I got it.
救命 好的 我稳住你了
Save me！Okay。I got you.
是动态感应器
The motion sensor.
躲起来 为什么灯光这么亮
Hide。Why is it so bright？
为什么这么暗
Why is it so dark？
过来这里 亲爱的
Come over here，honey。Come over here.
好的 快
Okay。Quick，quick.
好耶
Yes！
这么亮的灯得有多少流明啊
What's the lumen count on that thing？
天啊
Oh，man.
嘿 如果他们醒了怎么办
Hey，what if they're awake？
你在这里等着
Wait here.
现在是被缠上了
Now it's retangling.
转另一个方向 转 面向我
Go the other way。Now turn。Face.
缠得更紧了 转身
It's getting more wrapped up。Rotate.
你没帮上忙 我有在帮
You're not helping。Yes，I am.
好了 我弄好了 好
Okay。Yeah，I did it。Okay.
我绕到后面去
I'm going round back.
亲爱的圣诞老人
“亲爱的圣诞老人 我努力等你了 但我太困了 你可以直接进来”
「Dear Santa。I tried waiting up for you，but I'm too sleepy.
我给你留了灯 你的头号粉丝 麦克斯
Come on in！「
牛奶是辣的
Milk hot！
为什么牛奶是辣的
Why milk hot？
健怡 可乐
开始轰炸
Bombs away.
停 停
Stop！Stop！
看来妈妈说得没错 汽水不是好东西
You know，I guess my mum was right。Soda is bad for you.
等等 我们只是想要回娃娃⋯
Wait！We just want our doll
停 我们可以好好谈
Stop！We can talk.
你怎么会有这么多汽水
How the heck do you have so much soda？
我爸妈批发的 价格更便宜
My parents buy in bulk。It's more cost effective.
别想抓价值二十万的丑小孩
And forget about taking this $200，000 ugly boy.
我们不是来伤害你的
We're not here to hurt you.
请你冷静一些 我们好好谈
Please，just calm down，and we can talk about this rationally.
不要再扔汽水了 好吗
So easy on the soda，okay？
啊
Ouch！Ouch！
警报
Alarm！
圣诞老人 是你吗
Santa？Is that you？
嚯嚯嚯 你好吗 孩子
Ho！Ho！Ho！How are you，little boy？
桔色的花色球 中袋
Orange stripe，center pocket.
不
No！
听起来好疼哦
Ooh！That did not sound right.
好热又好冷哦
So hot and so cold at the same time.
杰夫
Jeff？
Jeff！
我在哪里
Where am I？
什么 这里是哪儿 我害怕
What？This。I'm scared.
怎么回事
What is this？
很好 我没事 手脚都还在
Okay。I'm okay。I have all my parts.
我是死了吗 我这是死了吗
Am I dead？Is this dead？
我站得太高了 太高了
That's too high！I'm too high.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like
你把我丢到了哪里
Where have you taken me？
你可以的 麦肯齐
You can do this，McKenzie.
我只需要跨过去 就只跳一小步
Okay，you just gotta make it across.
Just one small jump.
一 二 三
One，two，three！
杰夫
Jeff？
Jeff！
有东西顶着门
There's something blocking the door.
亲爱的
Oh，honey.
他攻击我 帕姆
He's hurting me，Pam.
我也是 亲爱的
Me too，baby。Me too.
那个英国小混蛋想要烧我
Little，limey monster tried to set me on fire.
他为什么要这么做 帕姆
Why's he doing this to us，Pam？
他说我们别想拿到二十万美元
He just told me our 200 grand is getting away.
娃娃在他手上 他知道娃娃的价值
He has our doll，and he knows what it's worth.
我们得拿回来
We have to get it back.
埃菲尔铁塔 你也来伤我？
The Eiffel Tower？Really？
不准说我不对 我这是为了我们家
Don't you dare judge me。I'm doing this for my family.
8小时11分后抵达
打探到什么了吗
You learned anything？
我打探到他有很多乐高积木
Just that this kid owns a lot of Legos.
我们进来了
We are coming in…
我忘记怎么用德语说“友好”了
I forgot the word for peace.
查一下 好的 看看
Yeah，look it up。Okay，let's see.
“友爱” 不对 “友善” “友谊”
「Pancake.」 No。「Potato.」 「Paralysis.」
我在这儿
Up here。Oh，hey.
好的 听着 我们只是想跟你谈谈
Okay。SoSo listen。We just wanna talk.
你能不能停下来跟我们谈谈
Would you just stop and talk to us？
拜托了
Please！
我们友好地进来了
We are coming in Frieden.
我知道“友好”怎么说了
Frieden is peace.
上来抓我啊
Come on up and get me！
啊
Ouch.
他在楼梯上涂了黄油
He put butter on the stairs.
又是面粉 又是牛奶 又是黄油的
Flour，milk and butter.
他想把我们做成饼干
He's turning me into a cookie.
要做饼干的话还需要糖
Well，you need sugar for a cookie.
糖
是谁家养了这么个小浑蛋
Who raised this little monster？
我们还是回家吧
I think we should go back home.
我们不能退缩
There is no going back.
我们已经这样了
This is who we are now.
这是我们选择的人生
This is the life we've chosen.
我们已经走上了坏的道路
We've gone to the other side.
你们找不到我哦
You'll never find me.
这个英国小鬼把我变成了针插
Harry Potter turned me into a pincushion.
很好 亲爱的 我这就来
Good job，honey。I'll be right there.
当我没说
Or not.
你好啊
Well，hello.
接着
Catch.
不会吧 竟然用这么软的瑜伽球来砸我
Oh，no。You hit me with the incredibly soft yoga ball.
抓住他 杰夫
Go get him，Jeff.
你们要放弃了吗 还是想再多来点
Given up yet？Or are you thirsty for more？
八号球 面部
Eight ball。Your face.
你现在跑不掉了 小鬼
There's nowhere to run now，little man.
那就等着瞧
We'll see about that.
拜拜
See ya.
帕姆 他从阳台跳下去了
Pam，he jumped off the balcony！
很好
Good.
是那件夹克
The jacket.
天啊 原来有梯子
Oh，no。A ladder.
你真以为我是傻子吗
You really think I'm that stupid？
对啊 我就是这么以为的
Yes。Yes，I do.
瓷娃娃
Dolly？
什么
What？
够了 你完了 小鬼
That's it。Time's up，little guy.
不
No！
够了
That's far enough.
你好啊
Well，hello there.
我会开枪的哦
I'll do it.
拜托 不要再射台球了
Please，please，please no more pool balls.
把枪放下
Drop the gun.
不可能
Not a chance.
我可不是吓唬你们
I'm not playing around，lady.
他真不是吓唬人 他今晚朝我射了好几个台球
He's not。He He shot me with several pool balls tonight.
够了
Enough！
该了结了
This stops here.
你惹错了人
You picked the wrong mom to mess with.
亲爱的 你还好吗
Honey，are you okay？
拜托 不要乐高积木和点火了
Please，no more Legos or fire
也不要图钉了 我们只想谈谈
or freaking thumbtacks。We just wanna talk.
是吗 我听到你们的计划了
Yeah，right。I heard your plan.
你们想要绑架我这个“丑小孩”
You wanna kidnap 「the ugly boy」
然后叫价二十万 把我卖给某个老太太
and sell me to some old lady for 200 large.
什么
What？
我才不丑 我妈妈说我是有个性
And I'm not ugly。My mum says I've got character.
你以为…
You thought
所以你才制造了这个死亡迷宫吗
Is that why you made this death maze？
孩子 我们只想要回我们的瓷娃娃
Kid，we just want our doll back.
什么瓷娃娃
What doll？
你从我们家偷的那个脸装错的丑娃娃
The one you stole from our house。The boy with the bad face。The ugly boy.
那个吗 我没偷呀
That？I didn't steal that.
我十岁了 我要娃娃做什么
I'm ten years old。Why on earth would I want a doll？
天啊 太糟糕了
Oh，no。This is bad.
我们做了糟糕的事情
We did a bad thing.
我们做了超级糟糕的事情
One of the worst bads we could've done.
我觉得我们得叫醒你的奶奶
I think we need to wake up your grandma.
你要打电话到英国叫我奶奶吗
You wanna call my grandma in England？
不 是住在这里的奶奶
No。The grandma who's staying here.
从德国来的那个
From Germany.
我奶奶没跟我住在一起呀
My grandma's not staying with me.
那么 那个人是谁
Well，then who is？
没别人 就我自己
No one。It's just me.
什么
What？
等等 你的爸妈呢
Wait，where are your parents？
在东京
Tokyo.
亲爱的 真抱歉
Oh。Sweetie，I am so sorry.
如果我们知道你是独自在家
If we had known you were staying here by yourself，
我们肯定换一个完全不同的方式了
we would've handled things a lot differently.
我们一次也不会闯入你们家
We wouldn't have broken into your home even once.
这是天大的误会
This was just a huge misunderstanding.
你把重型机枪放下来好不好
Now，why don't you just put that heavy gun down？
宝贝 过来
Oh，sweetie，come here.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
我们会照顾你的 好吗
We'll take care of you，okay？
好
Okay.
我知道这看起来像恶作剧
Okay，I know what it looks like…
但这真的是意外
But that was genuinely an accident.
希望如此
Well，I hope so.
因为 不
BecauseNo.
我得休息一下 我得坐下来
I gotta go take aI'm gonna go sit down.
好 我们给你爸妈打电话 跟他们报平安
Okay。Let's call your parents and let them know that you're okay.
在他们回来之前你可以和我们在一起
You can stay with us till they get back.
他们一定会修理我的
I'm gonna be in so much trouble.
不 亲爱的
No，honey.
你妈妈见到你一定会很开心的 我保证
Your mom is just gonna be happy to see you。I promise.
一开始开心
At first.
但接着你要完蛋了
ButBut then you'll be in trouble.
彻底完蛋 我可以想象
Pretty bad，I wouldI would imagine.
我们都要跟他们好好解释
I think we're all gonna have quite a bit of explaining to do.
你们闯进这孩子的家 因为你们以为他偷了瓷娃娃
Okay，so，you go to this kid's house，because you think he stole the doll…
你们在路上撞上了树 所以…
…and on the way there，you hit a tree，
which is why…
对
Yeah.
当你们到他家的时候 他独自在家吗
And then when you get to this kid's house，he's home alone？
对 差不多就是这样
Yes。Pretty much，yeah。Yes。Mmhmm.
哇
Wow.
你妈妈呢 你和她说了吗
How about your mom？Have you talked to her？
说了 她降落时我们给她打了电话
Yeah，we called her when she landed.
她高兴得哭了 没想到你们能让她不发火
She cried happy tears。I didn't even know you could do that.
所以 我们要搬家了吗
So，are we moving？
对不起 孩子们…
I'm sorry，guys…
有人给我们报了价
But we got an offer on the house，
我们没办法 只能接受
and we can't afford not to take it.
但没关系
But it's okay，
因为让这房子变得特别的是我们一家人
because what makes this house so special to us is us.
对吗
Right？
你妈妈说得很对
Your mum speaks a lot of sense.
没有爸爸妈妈的家 根本没有家的感觉
Without my mum and dad，my house really didn't feel like home.
亲爱的 会不会是开放日那天 来看房的人拿了娃娃
Oh，babe，what if one of those open house poacher people took the doll？
对 杰夫 你听说过这种事吗
Mmm，yes。Jeff，have you heard about this？
那种人会进你的家 把值钱的东西都偷走 很过分
They just come into your house and take all of your valuables。It's crazy.
知名法律主持在《新闻60分》里做过报道
Greta Van Susteren did a thing about it on 60 Minutes.
整集报道 对 整集报道
Full hour。Yeah。Full hour.
这谁知道呢 那个知名主持就知道
Who knows？Greta Van Susteren knows.
现在的情况是娃娃不见了 我们得…
But it's gone now，and，you know，we need to
奥利？
Ollie？
娃娃
Doll.
奥利 宝贝 你别动
Ollie，angel，do not move.
你真厉害
That was incredible.
你还好吗
Are you okay？
很好 我们都很好
Yeah。Yeah，I think we both are.
谁能想到奥利是大救星呢 对吧
Hey，who would've thought Ollie was gonna save the day，right？
耶 宝贝 干得好 干得好 小鬼
Yay，baby。Good job，my love。Good job，buddy.
妈妈
Mum！
麦克斯
Max。Mmm.
我把你丢下了 对不起 宝贝
Oh。I'm so sorry we left you，darling.
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
你有个好儿子
You've got a great kid.
对 没错
Yeah。Yeah，I really do.
他很有“创意”
He's very creative.
“创意” 对 他非常有“创意”
Creative。Yes。He's so creative.
谢谢 很高兴…
Thank you。That's nice to，um
看来那个小车祸还挺严重的
Wow，that really was some fender bender.
你看过那棵被撞的树就知道了
You should see the tree.
你要坐一坐吗
Oh。DoDo you wanna stay？
我们有很多蛋酒
Because we have a lot of eggnog.
他们的蛋酒多得都不知道该怎么办了
They got more nog than they know what to do with.
谢谢 但不用了
Oh。Uh，uh，thank you，but，uh，no.
我现在只想带这小家伙回家
I just wanna get this guy home now.
我从来没这么期待着想回家
Never been so excited to see my house.
那个…
Actually
对 家
Yes！Home。Mmmmm.
家是心灵的归宿
Home is where the heart is.
引自《阿拉巴马 甜蜜的家》
「Sweet Home Alabama.」
荷马的《奥赛德》也这么说
Homer's Odyssey.
故事的结局是什么 回家
Where do they wind up at the end？Home.
剧透警告
Spoiler alert.
你太小了 可能没读过 他们最后回家了
You're probably too young to have read it，but they end up at home.
是啊 太温馨了
Yeah，that's lovely.
没有比家更好的地方了 谢谢 谢谢
There is no place like home。Thank you。Thank you.
走吧 小家伙
Come on，you.
圣诞快乐 麦克斯
Merry Christmas，Max.
保重
Be good.
你也是
You too.
我想再抱你一下
Ooh。I need another hug.
我好想你
I missed you so much.
希望家里没被你弄乱
Hey，I hope the house isn't a mess.
哇
Wow.
她回家一定很高兴
She must be so happy to finally be home。Yeah.
是啊
因为家意味着家人 对吗
Because I guess home is just another word for family，right？
这是不是表示我们可以留在这里了
So，does that mean we get to stay here？
对 宝贝 没错 太好了
Yeah，sweetie。It does。Yes.
太好了
Yeah.
妈妈的肋骨疼
Mommy's ribs。Mommy's ribs are sore.
他们不穷了 真开心
So glad they're not poor anymore.
我觉得很不自在 真尴尬
It made me so uncomfortable。It was so awkward.
嘿 我们来开礼物吧
Hey，what do you say we open some presents？
Yes！Yes！
好啊
真想不到 天啊
Can I open the big one？Oh，my gosh！
圣诞快乐 圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas。Merry Christmas.
我要先开 我先开
I call opening first。Me first.
好了 孩子们 一次开一个
Okay，guys。One at a time.
好的 谢谢爸爸 谢谢
Thank you，Dad。Thank you.
我喜欢
I love it.
你不知道我有多想你
You wouldn't believe how much I missed you.
这将是我们两个人的圣诞节
It's just gonna be two of us for Christmas，hey？
一定很开心的 对吧
That'll be nice，won't it？Mmhmm.
天啊 多美好的一天啊
Oh，dear。What a day.
甜蜜的家
Home sweet home.
我可以跟你好好解释
There's a very reasonable explanation.
一年以后
我觉得他像一个小政客
I think he looks like a little politician.
妈妈 政客？ 他看起来像个政客
Mum，please。He looks like a politician.
可能是毛衣背心的缘故 他确实像个政客
Part of it's the sweater vest。He does look like a politician.
我喜欢 真的很喜欢 妈妈
I like it。I actually like it。Mum.
我都不知道… 好了 大伙儿 可以开动了
I don't even know anything about… Okay，everybody，time to eat.
这道菜看起来太棒了
Oh，this looks incredible.
非常感谢 你们的房子太美了
Thank you so much，and the house looks so beautiful.
不用谢我
Oh，don't thank me.
谢那个怪娃娃吧
Thank that creepy doll.
我们卖了它来支付各种费用 比如抵押贷款 欧洲旅行费…
Selling that paid for everything。Our mortgage，our trip to Europe…
还有你的新吊灯
And your new chandelier.
谢谢 还有干板墙
Thank you。And don't forget the drywall.
噢 是啊
Oh，yeah。Well
难怪我一直觉得这房子重新装修过了
I always thought the house could've done with a little remodeling anyway。So…
继续保持这些设置 特里 好的 祝好 好了 抱歉
Keep it on those settings，Terry。All right。Take it easy。All right。Sorry.
抱歉 大伙儿 是工作的事 很抱歉
Sorry，everybody。That was work。Apologies.
在圣诞节谈工作？
On Christmas Day？
杰夫被提升成为了地区经理
Jeff has been promoted to District Manager.
云是不过圣诞节的 迈克
There's no Christmas for the cloud，Mike.
云永远不休息
The cloud never sleeps.
我全天候提供云管理服务 包括…
And I provide 247 cloud management services。And that includes
爸爸
Dad.
我们干杯吧
Let's make a toast.
我可以喝一罐那个吗
Yes。Oh，um，can I get one of those？
它们的含糖量很高
You know，they're quite sugary.
我觉得我们得让他喝一罐汽水
I think we should let him have the soda.
还记得上一次的事吗
Remember what happened last time？
谢谢 小家伙 谢谢
There you go，buddy。Thanks.
干杯
Cheers.
敬新朋友
To new friends.
和家人
And family。Mmm.
祝我不会得永久性的神经损伤
And me having no permanent neurological damage.
很好
Yeah，that's good.
我要敬麦克斯 谢谢你让我们相识
And here's to Max for bringing us all together.
大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas，everybody.
圣诞快乐 圣诞快乐 干杯
Merry Christmas！Cheers.
圣诞快乐 宝贝 圣诞快乐 干杯 宝贝
Merry Christmas，darling。Merry Christmas。Cheers，darling.
大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas，everyone！